officialworldgolfranking.com 2016-11-21

# OWGR - Privacy Policy

**Website Privacy Policy**

This website is owned by Official World Golf Ranking Ltd (OWGR) and managed on their behalf by the PGA European Tour. OWGR recognises the importance of protecting personal privacy. This privacy policy outlines how OWGR collects, uses and protects information about you when you access the OWGR website. Whenever personal data is collected via your use of this website that information will only be used in accordance with this privacy policy and relevant legislation.

OWGR may occasionally amend this policy by updating this page. You should revisit the page from time to time to review any amendments.

**Official World Golf Ranking**

The Official World Golf Ranking ranks golfers in the world based on their average performance in eligible professional tournaments on a rolling cycle over the previous 104 weeks. This ranking is calculated in accordance with the rules established by The OWGR Governing Board, details of which can be found in the How the Ranking Works section of this Website.

In order to calculate such ranking, information about the players taking part in counting events and the scores that they achieve in such events are provided by the relevant professional Tours. This information is not submitted through the Website but is supplied directly by the organisers of the counting events, through affiliates of OWGR or collected via publicly available websites.

**The information we collect and how it is used**

Separate to the collection of information about players and their scores, information is also collected via the Website. We may collect the following personal and non-personal information from you:

We may collect personal information about people who provide feedback in relation to the Website using the Contact Us form.

We may use information we collect about you for providing you with services or information that you request from us or information which we feel may interest you, if you have agreed to be contacted for such purposes.

**Web Log Files**

In common with most websites we automatically log certain information about every visit to the site. This includes your IP Address and information relating to your requests from our servers, for example date and time, referrer, user agent (browser), request type and details of request size. The information is used to help us manage the website (e.g. detecting bugs). Under normal circumstances these log files will only be accessed by authorised members of staff, however we do have a legal obligation to make our log files available to external authorities such as the Police, when requested.

**How we use Cookies**

We would like to make you aware that cookies may be used on the Website. Cookies are small text files which are placed on your computer’s hard drive to help us monitor the use of our website and provide access to certain features. A cookie does not identify the individual only the computer used, it does not gives us access to your computer.

Cookies enable us to provide you with a better experience of our website. OWGR uses cookies to track user behaviour, improve and personalise the services we offer and remember previous actions.We do not use cookies which have a high impact on your privacy and will regularly review the use of cookies on our site to protect your privacy.

In common with many organisations OWGR uses ‘[Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/analytics/index.html)’ a web analytics service provided by Google Inc to enable us to analyse how our website is used. This means that information about use of our website may be transmitted to Google Inc. This information does not enable you to be identified and is not considered privacy intrusive. Users of the most popular web browsers can install a browser add-on which prevents information being transferred to Google, see <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

You can change the settings in your browser to refuse cookies. However in doing so you may be unable to access certain feature of our website. You can also delete cookies using the tools in your browser. For more information about cookies please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Security**

OWGR is committed to ensuring the security of the OWGR website and any information you provide using the site. OWGR has procedures in place to help protect against loss, misuse and alteration of information.

The OWGR website contains links to other websites which may be of interest to users. We are not responsible for the content of these websites and accept no responsibility for them or for any loss or damage that may arise from your use of them. The operators of other sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their own data protection or privacy policy. This privacy policy applies only to the Website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices within any other websites. You should always be aware of this when you leave the Website and we encourage you to read the privacy statement on any other website that you visit.

**Your Rights**

OWGR will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have informed you, have your permission or are required to by law. Information may be shared with third parties who are under contract to act for us.

OWGR takes its responsibilities under the Data Protection Act (DPA) seriously and will only process personal data in accordance with the Act.

Under the DPA you have the right to access your personal data held by the OWGR for a small fee. If you wish to obtain this information, please write to or email us at the address set out below.

If you believe the information we are holding on you is incorrect or you require further information about how we use your information please write to us or email us at the address set out below.

**How to contact us**

Please contact us if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or the information we hold about you.

Email us: **worldranking@owgr.com**

Write to us:

**OWGR Ltd  
European Tour Building   
Wentworth Drive   
Virginia Water   
Surrey   
GU25 4LX   
United Kingdom**

1An IP address is a unique number or address given to every computer or device when it connects to a network allowing it to be identified and communicated with.
